DR. VICTOR POZZOBON

PhD research scientist leading numerous investigations in microalgal biotechnology. My goal is to help microalgae to realise the full extend of their potential. To do so, I deploy both experimental and numerical tools. The current focus of my research is increasing culture cell density in photo and/or heterotrophic mode.



CONTACT

- victor.pozzobon@yahoo.com
- **433 (0) 623 641 98**
- 6 rue des sports, 08300 Rethel, France
- victorpozzobon.github.io
- in Victor Pozzobon
- 0000-0003-1530-0834

SOFT SKILLS

Team leading

Empathy Decision making Problem solving



Languages

English
French
German

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Numerics

Programming (e.g. Python, C++, Bash, ...)

(e.g. Python, C++, Bash, ...) CFD

(OpenFOAM, Fluent, Comsol)

Visualisation
Machine Learning



Biotechnology

Basic lab techniques Advanced lab techniques (Flow cytometry, PAM, ...)

Modelling Microalgae



CERTIFICATES

MOOCS

Data analysis - 2020 HPC Python - 2020 Management & leadership - 2020 Numerical analysis - 2017 Mathematical biostatistics - 2015

Food & nutrition - 2015 Athletes physiology - 2015 Human physiology - 2014

WORK HISTORY

October 2020 - To date

Head of the modelling team

♦ Chair of Biotechnology CentraleSupélec. Pomacle. France

Managing a team of 5 people. Structuring research projects and acquiring funding Key driver: implementing the digital twin concept in microorganisms biotechnology

Movember 2015 - October 2020

Chair of Biotechnology CentraleSupélec, Pomacle, France Research engineer

Principal Investigator on microalgae/light interaction. Numerous involvement in biological experiments and associated modelling

Key realisations: full scale CFD modelling of a photobioreactor. Coupling with biological model to predict performance. Wild strain profiling

EDUCATION

September 2020

• INP Toulouse HDR

Thesis title: Modeling as a tool for chemical and biochemical engineering

Novembre 2015 - September 2012

RAPSODEE Mines Albi, Albi, France

PhD

Thesis title: Biomass gasification under high solar heat flux.

September 2008 - September 2012

September 2000 September 2012
 Engineering degree

Chemical engineering with academic exchange in fluid dynamics (with Honors)

POSITIONS, COLLABORATIONS, PUBLICATIONS

- ▼ French users of OpenFOAM, FOAM-U association. Secretary (2016-2020). Treasurer (2020-to date)
- $oldsymbol{\P}$ Research partnerships, with co-authored publications:

RAPSODEE - Mines Albi

RIBP - Université Reims Champagne Ardenne

LPQM - CentraleSupélec

IFPEN - Solaize

ABI - AgroParisTech

Agglometated research indicators: h-index - 8, 27 authored or co-authored articles in peer reviewed rank A journals

TEACHINGS AND TRAININGS

A brief graphical summary of my teachings activities. My formal teachings represent about 80 h and one or two OpenFOAM bootcamp (2 to 3 days)

